I think this isn't new news, but it's u
it's good to get him back in back in the
building and [clears throat] I think we
all know how uh the energy that Eric
brings um and what he gives to a
football team. So, and he's
[clears throat] coming off a heck of a
season with the the Chicago Bears. My
hat goes off to the Bears and the great
job that they did there.
And then um on the other hand, we we had
another great coordinator here too with
Matt Naggie and and uh this gives Matt
an opportunity to go out and run his run
his show there and um do what he does
best uh taking two Super Bowl
championships with him and three Super
Bowl appearances. So, uh he'll uh and a
top 10 offense that he he was working
with this this past year. So, he'll go
out and be able to put his own mark on
things and and uh that takes my name off
of it and he gets the purity of it. I
was hoping that it would be a head
coaching position. It still might be
that he he deserves that for definitely
for sure. Um and uh if that doesn't
work, it gives him an opportunity to
step in as a coordinator and run a show
uh from there. So, um it's a win-win, I
think, on both sides for both both
coaches. And um again, we're just we're
glad that EBE was able to come back in
and and uh jump in in that position
[clears throat] and bring all the
knowledge that he has uh likewise to the
to the table. So with that, time's
yours.
>> Let's start with Sam McDow.
>> Hey Andy. Um and savv.
Uh, first, you know, I mean, those of us
who who were at training camp every day,
I mean, can certainly see the impression
that that EB leaves out there on the
players and on the field, but in what
ways did you notice that you needed that
back?
>> Yeah. Well, I thought Matt brought great
energy, too, with his. It's just it's
different. It's a different um they both
have their own personalities that they
they share with it. and EB
[clears throat]
does he he's going to um be very
[clears throat] direct with the players,
very direct with um the the coaches and
it it it's a it's a different flavor. Uh
both have been very uh productive in
this in this system here. So I I think
it's u it's a win-win for
um for us that way. But EB brings the
there's nobody like EB on the field that
way. He that's one of his and and uh
with the players, he does a great job
there.
>> Obviously, when you've got an opening,
you you could go several different ways
with it and you choose to go with with
EB. Just wondering if you interviewed
anyone from the outside and kind of what
your thought process was on prioritizing
what EB brings versus maybe what what
somebody else might have brought. No, I
did talk to you. EB was in the playoffs,
so I didn't wasn't able to talk to him
until after he was done there. So, um,
but had to make a move faster. There
were a lot of openings here, Sam. And
so, if, uh, one guy's going one
direction, you got to make sure that you
can fill that fill that position and and
do it as quickly as you possibly can.
So, um, at the same time of still being
able to talk to others. So, to answer
your question, yes, I did talk to other
people.
Let's go next to Jesse Newell.
>> Hey Sid, I'll have a quick followup,
too. Hey, Andy, just to start off with,
you seem pretty fired up about this. Can
you go into why this hire fires you up?
>> Well, listen, I'm fired up to get in
this off season and get going. I mean,
we didn't do very well this past year,
and that's not been our MO there. So, I
I I want to fix a problem and let's
let's uh [clears throat] um the problems
that we had and and um in all phases.
This isn't just an offensive in all
phases. We've had [clears throat] some
guys that have have have uh you know
that some there'll be people that move
on. There'll be people that come in
players
um and a couple of quality control guys
left and a couple other guys left. And
so, uh, we'll cover all that down the
road here, but it's, uh, um, you know,
it change can be good sometimes for you
and and so that's what I'm fired up
about.
>> And what do you think EB is specifically
going to do for Patrick at this point in
his career?
>> Yeah. I mean he he brings it Patrick
knows him first of all Jesse and then I
tell you uh Eie will be very direct with
him like he does with everybody and
um and but he he knows it's coming from
a place of knowledge there that he he
knows and and [laughter] and Patrick you
guys could take this whole thing a
couple different ways so I want to make
sure we're saying this right. Patrick
loved
um Nags and he also loves EB. So, it's
not it's this isn't uh this isn't either
either or deal. It's uh um one guy
having to replace another guy to that's
not what this is about. Um but I want to
make sure Naz gets his shout out here
too and that EB gets his uh gets his for
coming in here.
Let's go next to Vah.
>> Hey Andy. Um, just curious if you could
speak to this a little bit. As
meticulous as you are about everything,
I I I wondered to what degree this this
is, you know, a process where you wrote
down a lot of things you were looking
for and you you you or you just had to
think about this and and Eric just came
to mind. I know you talk to other
people, but I wonder if you could just
share that a little bit about what you
sought and how how much this is gut.
>> Yeah. So,
I know both guys and know them well.
I've worked with them hand in hand, won
championships with them. And so here's
Nags in a position where he's
um he's got an opportunity here
potentially to to move on and great
things happen for he and his family and
everything else. So, um I'm on one side
of that. I'm pushing that. I'm saying,
"Let's go, man. Do your thing." And on
the other side, I've got to sit there
and go, "Who's going to replace this guy
that just came off of uh winning a
couple championships and and going to
three Super Bowls?" So, um, you know, EB
becomes an obvious [clears throat]
guy that you'd want to talk to, I would
I would think, right, from a logical
standpoint. So, um, I I think he's a
he's a great fit. [clears throat] He was
a great fit when he was here. He'll be a
great great fit now that he's back. And
I've had success with bringing guys back
into the fold and things happening.
[laughter] And so as a unit, as a
organization, and um I think everybody's
fired up to see that listen, we're able
to replace a great guy with another
great guy. I've got great guys here.
I've got I mean, Joe Blame there there
very few guys are as good as Joe Blame.
I feel very confident in him in that
offensive room. And we've, you know,
Spags and his crew are here. So it's
it's there's just some uh you know, Andy
Hex. I mean, these guys are all guys
that are top top-notch and and then
Brett's working the personnel side of
it. So, it's a there's good continuity.
There's good teamwork that goes on. I
know everybody can function well
together. That becomes important to me.
>> And I'm sorry I lost track of what's
official and not official at this point,
but it it
>> Well, don't ask it if it's not official.
T
>> Luckily, you'll know. Um,
in general, it looks like there there
are uh, you know, a handful of other
changes to the
>> Yeah, I don't want I I don't want to get
into all that. Hey, we'll we'll we'll
hit that another time. I don't want to
take anything away from EB and and him
coming back here because that I think is
a I think for everybody, for our fan
base, for ownership, for the
organization, I just think is a it's a
positive thing. At the same time,
um, I I want Matt I want Matt to have a
chance to be a head football coach and
do the things that he he's dreaming of
doing. I mean, that's that's huge in
this business. And he's sitting at at a
[clears throat]
at an important time that that, you
know, with with some openings in this
league that you very seldom see where
you've got these 10 at one time here, 10
different openings. I mean, that's uh
there's opportunities there.
>> Thanks, Andy.
>> Yeah. Let's go next to Pete Sweeney. Go
ahead, Pete.
>> I was just wondering a little bit about
the the Matt uh aspect of it. You know,
from your words, it sounds like it was
sort of a mutual positive parting of
ways. I guess when did you determine uh
that would be um best or I guess the two
of you determin determined that would be
best. And um again, just to confirm, it
just feels like he can put his stamp uh
on something somewhere else and that
that being the reason.
>> Yeah, if we if we left it that simple,
that that's what I would tell you. I
mean, I know there's everybody's going
to question everything and I get all
that. It's understandable. But Matt and
I had a have a great relationship and
here he sits and uh and and before the
season, you know, right at before the
season even started here, um I knew that
he wanted an opportunity to have his own
show. He's been a head coach. He was
coach of the year. I mean, this this
guy, all the things I've said about him,
I still feel about him. There's there's
nothing different there. He he he uh he
deserves to have a head coaching job and
um if not it gives him it gives him an
opportunity to go out and do his thing.
I would I would have told you the same
thing about EB when he did it. It gave
him an opportunity to go out and do
their thing. So there was no signage of
rollovers and all that. He just he
wanted to just keep it that way. Word
gets out on that and give them an
opportunity. And I mean, somebody's
missing [laughter] missing a gym here. I
just that's how I feel. And I would I
would love to see him get picked up and
and going. And at the same time, we got
back a gym. So, it's a it's a win. It
has a chance to be a win-win here uh
when everything's said and done.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Go next to Todd Lebo.
>> Hey, coach. Eric left and got to be in a
couple of different places and, you
know, dip his toe in some other stuff.
What sort of things do you think he
learned while he was away that he could
maybe help?
>> Yeah. Everywhere you go in this
business, you pick something up and um
and you might take it with you or you
might say, you know what, that that was
I'm not going to do that. I don't want
to do that. So um and at the same time
he's got all those years in this in this
uh system too. So he understands that.
So I welcome that. always keep my, you
know, ears and eyes open for things. And
um that's why we're very seldom stagnant
and and uh why even with our record, I I
felt where I could stand in front of you
guys and go, listen, what worked for us
the year before,
it just flipped on us. We the games we
won the year before, uh they flipped on
us this year and we we didn't win.
[clears throat] And um and that's
sometimes how this thing works. Um, and
so now it's making sure that we get back
and do the right do what you know and
correct some things and then get them
going in the right direction again. So,
but at the same time, you finish and
you're looking at being in the top 10
offensively. I mean, before Pat gets
hurt or after even after the Dallas
game, which didn't go our way. I mean,
here's Matson with a top five offense,
you know, in a lot of categories in the
NFL. So, I respect that part. this game.
We're seeing it now when you look at the
playoffs. I mean, these games are nip
and tuck, baby. It's uh it's you make a
miss a play here or there and you're
going to lose the game. And so, all
those games that were so tight for us
this year, we've got to we have to fix
it and and clean that up.
>> Guys, we're going to wrap this up with
Seren and Matt Derek. Um we got to get
coach on to a meeting.
>> Okay.
>> Go ahead, Sin.
>> Thank you. And and I'll have a a
followup as well.
>> You've only got one minute surrender.
>> That's it. One I'll go quick. Uh one of
the things uh um when Patrick spoke to
us, he said that he was looking for and
and was accountability. He used that
word. I mean, is that a It seems like
for as an outsider that accountability
is something that Eric is certainly not
afraid to make sure. And is is that
something that you think was lacking
last year when you hear your quarterback
say that? No, I think Pat probably said
it best right there is that we've always
had accountability here. Uh with Eric or
or without Eric, it was still, you know,
you're responsible for certain things.
Um and so whoever is coming in uh better
be be feeling that [laughter] and and uh
there's a certain standard that that
you're going to hold each other to. and
and um I think I I would I'm sure that's
what Patrick was without quizzing him
here. Seren, I I would tell you that
that's probably what he was saying.
>> Uh he he also said someone who would
bring in uh new ideas, bring new ideas
every day, I think was the way uh he
phrased it. I know you've had different
people come in whether it was I think it
was Chris Alt was the Nevada coach. And
you know, you this offense obviously
looks real different than say the way
Bill Walsh was running it with the
49ers, right? you've never been afraid
to to change and and and adapt. Is that
something you have to, you know,
constantly remind yourself that it needs
to happen? Do you do you when you win,
when you have the kind of success you
guys have, is it are you liable to maybe
fall into a rut and not look for the
different kind of changes that that
maybe you would otherwise?
>> Yeah, you know, I think we do I think we
do a good job with that. We try to give
you a little different flavor every year
and stay ahead of things. Um, I I think
we've got to do a better job all the way
around and every every area. Just I I
think that's important. Um, and so you
go through and you hammer this thing
out. You take every offensive play,
every defensive player, every special
teams play. You go through it. You make
sure that you've got guys that are aware
of the the league and how things go
there, different [clears throat] trends
offensively, defensively, and on special
teams. and and um you use all the
technology that's out there. There's no
reason uh to be stagnant. You've got too
many different options. You shouldn't
have to bring in the latest greatest
here and there and all that. That's not
um you you've got all that right at a
fingertip for you if you want to go that
route.
>> Okay, we'll wrap this up with U Matt
Derek. Go ahead, Matt.
>> Hey, coach. Um one quick question. How
[clears throat] do you anticipate play
calling work with with Eric? That was
one of the big things when he left was,
you know, his ability to call his own
plays and kind of have his own offense.
How do you anticipate play calling
working with him coming back?
>> Yeah. So, listen, I mean, I still enjoy
calling plays and but what I do is I
also I'm not afraid to delegate and get
opinions from people and then even in
certain situations letting them go ahead
and call things in in different areas.
So, we we do this jointly. I I keep it
open and I felt that that's the best way
you I want guys that contribute. I want
them to work hard and be expert in their
area as in uh and then cumulatively in
all areas. So it's uh I [clears throat]
I've always
mixed and matched there I guess I tell
you Matt and it's it seemed to have been
fairly productive.
>> And you've mentioned that you know you
want to get things fixed and cleaned up
from what went wrong in 25. What do you
feel like is the biggest way that EB can
can do that? What's the area where you
feel like he can make the biggest
impact?
>> First of all, I'm going to tell you
this, Matt. Find a year where I haven't
said that. Now, maybe maybe you can blow
it up, but every year I'm going to tell
you whether we win the Super Bowl or
not, man. We got there's areas that we
got to go through and hash out here and
make sure we we get better at. So, I
think that's every year. I think it's
every game. If you can kind of keep that
mentality through the day, you're going
to be okay. Um, and and get yourself
better. [clears throat] But I think he
be what are some of his strengths. Um I
I think he's got a great knowledge of
the offense. I think he's um understands
leadership. I've always said he's a
great leader of men, whether it's
coaches, players. I think he does a heck
of a job there. Um he's good with you
guys. He's very honest with you. And
there there's no hidden uh agendas. I
mean, that's just his personality and
and not listen, we're not we're talking
about EB here. So, I'm not talking about
Matt Naggie. That's not what we're
doing. We're not comparing here. We're
This is EB. You asked me his strengths,
those are his strengths.
>> Thank you, everybody. Uh, thank you,
coach.
>> Thank you guys for sticking with that
tip. Thank you.